This is the precious bottle I got by passing Ioryogi's test.
When this bottle is filled, my wish will be granted,
and I'll be able to go to that place, right, Ioryogi?
I wonder when it'll fill up?
Let's look forward to it!
Hey.
You're the one who's supposed to fill it, Kobato!
What shall I do?
Even the obvious things are always so hard
I just want to grin when I'm happy, sing when I'm in love
They say my dreams will come true someday
but when will someday come? I can't wait!
Count one, two, three and spread my arms
Gather the light to myself
Where is it? Tell me what I can do
Even if I'm hurt so much, even if I run so hard
Even if I collapse crying over and over, I still
believe in my amazing future
Hanato Kobato!
Yes!
... Sparkling candy.
Just getting the bottle doesn't mean anything, okay!?
What are you filling that bottle with!?
People's scarred hearts, Ioryogi!
And what do you need to do to collect those!?
I must heal their scarred hearts!
All right!
Looks like you've got the basics.
So let's get collecting!
Yes!
Oh, I forgot to mention one thing.
Don't talk to me when there are people around.
Why?
Since you lack any memory, knowledge, or common sense, I'll explain.
Stuffed animals don't talk here.
You understand that talking to things that can't talk back is weird, right?
Why don't they talk?
Because they're stuffed animals.
Why don't stuffed animals talk?
Just get going!
Okay!  I'll try my best!
Don't just suddenly get off the see-saw!
Is anyone here scarred?
Do any of you want to be healed?
Are any of you scarred?
Let me heal your heart!
No thanks, I'm fine.
Excuse me!  Is there anything I can do to heal you?
Hey, come on.
Is there anything I can do to help you?
Rock, paper, scissors!  Here goes!
Hey, lady, help us out!
With what?
You can be it when we play kick the can!
Huh?  Will it help you if I'm it?
Yeah, please!
Okay, I'll try my best!
Kick the can!
Huh, that's funny.  There's nothing in here yet.
How does being it in kick the can heal anyone?
There isn't anyone whose heart would be healed by that.
Really?
You're not doing anything but being a playmate.
I see...
I guess it's pretty tough to just run into someone who wants to be healed.
But if there's no one that wants to be hurt, that means there's no one sad, no one scarred!  It's great!
Man, you think positive about everything.
It'd be great if I could find a way to help out...
Uh...  Excuse me...
Here you go.
You're giving this to me?
Yeah, go ahead.
To be able to just walk up to someone and give them something wonderful like this...
What a wonderful person!
Come on.
I've gotta reel a few more people in...
It'd be great if you'd take as many as you want.
Really?  Then I'll take them all!
Thanks!  You're a real help!
Not only did I help him out, I got plenty of something wonderful!
What are you gonna do with all of those?
Now it's my turn to give everyone something this wonderful!
Here!  Have some wonderful tissues!
They're sure to be useful!  Here you go!
Here!
I'll give you plenty!
I've already got plenty.
Here, go right ahead!
Here!  Here!
Have some wonderful tissues!
Damn, you're annoying.
I'm sorry!
Hey.
Yes?
Quit screwing around in the middle of the road.
I'm sorry!
That person...
from before...
Clean up the tissues.
Wait!  Let me thank you!
I think he's over here...
The sheets went flying!
Over here, Miss Sayaka!
What are you doing?
Oh no!
Are you okay?
Yes...
Her nose has a scrape!
Really!
This is embarrassing...
Come on, stop laughing.
Okay, Miss Sayaka!
I'm sorry.
This is Yomogi Nursery.  I work here.
We've so few people working that I have to do the laundry.
You don't have many workers?
It's inconveniencing you?
Well, yes.
Would having more people help you?
Well...
Would it help you?
Yes.
Then I'll help out!
Here, take these!
Thank you.
Hey, what's your name?
I'm Toshihiko!
I'm Hanato Kobato!
Kobato?
That's a funny name!
It's a funny name!
I guess.
So your dad must be Ohbato!
Nope.
So what's he named?
What's he named?
Um...
What's his name?
What's he named?
Hey!
What?
Hey...
You don't have a dad?
Yeah...
Then his name doesn't matter!
Let's play!
Let's go on a date!
Stay out of her way, everyone.
Okay, Miss Sayaka!
Um...  What should I help out with?
Just keep them occupied like that.
Keep them occupied...
Umm...
Miss Kobato!
Yes?
Play the organ!
I'm sorry, I don't know how.
Oh...
I'm sorry.
But we can all dance together!
You can dance!?
Yes!
Wait!
Hey, Mr. Kiyokazu, come play the organ!
We're gonna dance with Miss Kobato!
She's not a teacher.
Okay...  Kobato then!
What are you doing following me around?
I just wanted to say thanks.
Fine.  Now go home.
But I'm helping out here!
You can't even play the organ.
You're useless.
Oh, you two are friends?
Wrong!
I see.
This is Fujimoto Kiyokazu.  You'll be working with him.
And this is Kobato.
Try to get along today.
Okay!
Stay out of my way.
Come on and play the organ, Mr. Kiyokazu!
Hurry up, teacher!
All right, I'm leaving this to you.
Kobato too!
Let's dance!
What's up with that?
He's such a meanie!
I won't lose!
Is this where they live?
They don't live here, we just take care of them during the day.
I see.
But it's kind of old.
There's a new nursery nearby too, so fewer and fewer kids are coming here.
But!
We've gotta do our best!
Well, there's no point in just worrying.
You're right, Fujimoto.
Thanks.  You really helped us out, Kobato.
The kids had a lot of fun with you too.
Come on, I just played with them!  That kind of thing always drives Ioryogi up the wall.
Oh no!  Ioryogi's gone!
Your friend?
Yeah!  He's the stuffed animal I always carry around!
I was carrying him around because he can't talk to come get me!
Excuse me!
Wait, should I come back tomorrow?
If you don't mind.
Miss Sayaka.
We don't know where she lives or what she's up to.
Do we really want her around the kids?
It's not like you don't know!  I'm Hanato Kobato!
Do you really think your name is a good enough answer?
I'm--!
What?
Trying to figure it out myself...
Well...
If you can, we'd love to have you!
Even though we can't really pay you...
No!  If I can help out, that's more than enough!
All right, then.
Hey.
Yes?
I'll tell you one thing.
If you're just doing this out of pity or self-sacrifice, stay away.
Thinking "poor us" or "it's so tough" is just annoying.
I don't think that at all!
Um...
Get in the way...
Get in the way, huh.
Like leaving me behind in the middle of town all of a sudden!
I'm glad you found me!
Quit being glad!
Do you know what would've happened if someone had walked off with me!?
I'm sorry!
Didn't I tell you?  I'm a stuffed animal here!
Stuffed animals don't just walk off on their own!
I'm sorry!
Never mind the bottle, you forgot me!
The bottle?
I knew it...
What do you mean, you knew it?
Did you really expect anything in there?
So what I did didn't heal anyone...
I just annoyed them.
Fujimoto seemed so scarred, though.
But he said I was annoying.
Well, it varies from person to person.
There's both scarred and unscarred people out there,
but out of the people that are scarred,
I didn't know there were both people who wanted and who didn't want to be healed.
And?
Mm?
What are you gonna do?
I'll...
If you wanna heal him, do it.
Should I?
Doesn't matter if you should or shouldn't, worry about that after you do it.
Okay!
Let's go home!
That's...
Toshihiko?
Kobato...
Does the nursery send kids home now?
Yeah, but I'm not going yet.
Do you like swings?
Not a ton.
But I've gotta wait here a little more before Mom comes.
She has work.
Work, huh.
But she's a hard worker!
Even though she's been having a hard time since the divorce, she makes me breakfast!
She's nice!  Really!
That's amazing!
Aren't you going to say she's no good?
At what?
Is your mom late again, Toshihiko?
I see.  You're so wise, not being selfish.
Again, Toshihiko?  You're such a good boy waiting patiently like this.
It's too bad your mother doesn't care a little more for you.
Right?
Maybe she's working herself too hard.
Everyone says I have a bad mom.
That mom's no good.
A no-good mom?
Wrong!  Mom's a hard worker!
Really!  She's really great!
That's wonderful.
It's wonderful to have such a great, hard-working mom.
Really?
Yeah!  She's a wonderful mom!
What's wrong?
Are you hurt?
Wrong!
Really?
It's filling up!
But why?
It's from that boy Toshihiko.
Toshihiko?
Hey, hey!
Kick, Kobato!
Toshihiko, you're great!
Hey, try harder!
He was so happy that you were kind to him and praised his mother.
So...  I was kind?
If you've got ulterior motives, just being kind won't heal people.
You should keep doing what you did there.
Okay!
I'll try my best to collect people's scarred hearts!
Wait, hold it!
That sounds like you're scarring them yourself!
Then...  Their healed hearts?
That makes it sound like you're snatching them away right after healing.
Then...  What should I call these?
Stop bothering me about it!
They look like candy, call 'em that.
Candy...
Got it!  I'll call these candy!
Hey, Kobato!
Yes?
There!
Abandoning me is inexcusable, but what came before that was great.
I'm giving you 100 points!
Keep it up, Kobato!
Okay!
I'll try my best!
Don't get carried away just because you scored 100!
But you said to keep it up!
That's not what I meant!
Then what should I do?
Never mind!  No 100 for you!
Come on!
People all want to fly
but they're cheated by gravity
everyone can really fly
She must be so unhappy because
she forgot her own shadow somewhere
Then...
If you say it thankfully, if you do it thankfully
Together, we'll be happy
You'll be happy, there'll be nothing to worry about
As long as we're together
It's strange, I'm crying even though I'm happy
... Gift of the rain.
Next episode